# **Aaron Barrichello Pattinama**

■ aaronpattinama2004@gmail.com □ +62 851-5520-3887 🖿 in/aaronbarrichello

### **SUMMARY**

Being responsible, able to collaborate effectively, and a fast learner are some of my strengths. I have a keen interest in the field of information technology, especially cyber security. I have participated in several study groups on cyber security and learned a lot from them. I also have internship experience in project management, which has equipped me with the skills to handle projects effectively. Additionally, I have honed my soft skills through participation in various committees and joining organizations. This makes me a reliable individual.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Staff of Interest And Talent

### Himpunan Mahasiswa S1 Informatika

June 2024 - Present, Telkom University

- Coordinator for the Informatics Band Community (Rythmics)
- · Managing all relation between the Informatics Band Community (Rythmics) and Informatics Student Association (HIMA IF)

### Study Group Participant (Digilearn)

### Multimedia, Big Data, and Cyber Security Lab

May 2024 - June 2024, Telkom University

- · Learn About Cyber Security: Introduction to Cyber Security, Learn how to use Virtual Machine, Learn about Linux Operating System, Reconnaissance & Information Gathering
- Learn about Geographic Information System: Introduction to ArcGIS, make a mobile app UI using figma, make a 3d objects using blender, make AR & VR using unity
- · Learn about Big Data: Introduction to Big Data, Preprocessing and Data Cleansing, Data Visualization
- · Learn About Game Tech: Design objects using Adobe Illustrator, Learn to create movement using unity

### **Study Group Participant**

Internet of Things LAB TEL-U

April 2024 - June 2024, Telkom University

· Learn about the basic of arduino

### **Project Management Intern**

### **Mobile Innovation Laboratory**

December 2023 - March 2024, Telkom University

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Providing business ideas.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Creating Product Requirements Document and Business Model Canvas.
- · Leading and directing the work of technical staff until the project is successfully completed.
- · Acting as a liaison between business and technical aspects of the project.

### Logistics

### Perseketuan Mahasiswa Kristen

November 2023 - December 2023, Telkom University

· Prepare all the necessary equipment and items, as well as secure the venue permits.

## **Study Group Participant**

## **Security Laboratory**

October 2023 - November 2023, Telkom University

- · Learned about basic linux & password cracking
- · Learned about web exploit (cookie manipulation) using ffuf & burpsuite
- $\cdot \ Learned\ about\ Social\ Engineering\ techniques\ using\ tools\ like\ Seeker, facadıng\ \&\ Storm-Breaker$
- · Learned about digital forensic

### **Public Relation**

#### Carnival 2023 - HIMA IF

October 2023 - November 2023, Telkom University

- · Carnival is an event organized by the HIMA IF to celebrate the graduation ceremony and show appreciation to the graduates.
- · My task is to gather as many informatics students from Telkom University to participate in this event.

### **Hacker Class Participant**

## Forensic And Security Laboratory

June 2023 - July 2023, Telkom University

- · Short course to prepare for CTF competition
- $\cdot \ Learned \ and \ practiced \ about \ Web \ Exploitation, \ Cryptography, \ Reverse \ Engineering, \ Binary \ Exploitation, \ and \ Penetration \ Testing$

### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Informatics**

Telkom University • Bandung, Indonesia • 3.64

## **Software Engineering**

SMK Telekomunikasi Telesandi  $\cdot$  Bekasi, Indonesia  $\cdot$  2022

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

## R Fundamental for Data Science

DQLab · 2021

# Python Fundamental for Data Science

DQLab · 2021

# Fundamental SQL Using SELECT Statement

DQLab · 2021